Curriculum Vitae Gourab Paul

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Gourab Paul



- Whitefield, Bangalore, 560037, India
- (+91) 903-583-8711
- gourab.p17@gmail.com
- https://gourab.oyekool.com
- Skype: gourab.p17 | LinkedIn: http://in.linkedin.com/in/gourabpaul

Sex Male | Date of birth 17/10/1989 | Nationality Indian

PREFERRED JOB

After having 6.5 years' of experience with many role and responsibility in software industry, I am looking for new opportunity, either as a full-stack developer, cloud computing, java developer, micro services, machine learning or similar position. I have experience working as a lead developer in start-ups as well as an individual contributor in multinational company with various clients/teams across various countries.

WORK EXPERIENCE

July, 2017 - present

Module Lead System (Lead developer)

Mphasis- https://www.mphasis.com/. Client: HP Inc - https://hp.com

- Enablement service: Design and develop micro service application in AWS lambda to fetch printer details from PAAS and K2 system and make a single point of contact for both fulfilment need(service delivery) and doppler service.
- JamPublisher: Migrate existing MSSQL database to PostgreSQL and change the respective ORM and java-hibernate. And deploy the same in AWS RDS instance and ECS container
- Billing service: Wireframe and develop billing UI for Staples, JP Morgan and Kaiser client using Angular5 and Typescript and generate ms excel and pdf using handlebars
- Technology/Tools Angular 5, Angular material, angular-cli, Node js, JsReport, Git,
 Visual Studio Code, NodeJs, Serverless(sls), DynamoDb, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Amazon
 Web Services, Lambda, api gateway, Git, Npm, Visual Studio Code, Java, MSSQL,
 PostgreSQL, api gateway, Kibana, Tomcat, Jenkins, Docker, Pipeline, ECS, Liquibase,
 Maven, Spring
- Team size: 5 Process : Agile(Scrum), TFS

Jan, 2017 – July, 2017

Senior System Engineer (Lead Cloud Engineer)

IBM- https://www.ibm.com/. Client: DTCC - http://www.dtcc.com/

- Migrate existing monolithic service oriented architecture(SOA) Credit derivatives warehouse to microservices and serverless api using Node Js and Angular 2/4
- Technology/Tools NodeJs, PassportJs, Restify, Mongoose, MongoDB, sequelize, postgresql, Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Amazon Web Services, Lambda, Spring-boot, api, Bitbucket, Angular2/4, Typescript, SPA(Single Page application), Gulp, Visual Studio Code IDE
- Team size: 8 Process : Agile(Scrum), Jira

Curriculum Vitae Gourab Paul

May, 2016 – Jan, 2017

Senior Software Engineer (Lead developer)

Niranta Solutions & Services Pvt Ltd - http://www.niranta.in/. Project: Talhunt

- Develop products using Spring MVC and Node.js on the back end, Angular JS (SPA) at the front end, and Google Cloud(Firebase) for authentication for ATS(automatic tracking system) and HRM(human resource management)
- O Technology/Tools Node js, AWS(EC2, EBS, Route 53, Cloud front, SES, SQS, SNS, RDS), Google cloud(Bucket, Firebase), Spring JDBC, Spring mvc, rest apis, Java Mailer, Velocity Template, MySql, Junit, Maven, Intellij IDE, Apache tomcat 7, BitBucket, Angular Js, Bootstrap 3, HTML5, Yeoman, Bower, Grunt, Visual Studio Code IDE
- Team size: 8 Process : Agile(Scrum, Kanban), TFS

Nov, 2015 - May, 2016

Java Developer (Software Consultant)

Quantiphi - https://www.quantiphi.com/. Client: HeavyWater - https://www.heavywater.com/

- Design and deployed web application and micro services for research analysis of OCR extracted insurance paper using Amazon Web Services for laaS(EC2, load balancers), PaaS(S3) and SaaS(SWF)
- Technology/Tools Amazon Web Services, AWS EC2, AWS Dynamo DB, AWS SWF, Cloud Computing, AWS S3, J2EE, RESTful Web Services (CXF and Jersey), Microservices, Junit, Mockito, Maven, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Eclipse IDE, Agile(Scrum)
- Team size: 10 Process : Agile(Scrum), Jira

Mar, 2013 - Nov, 2015

Senior System Engineer (Software developer)

Tata Consultancy Services - https://www.tcs.com/ .

- **OM** (Client: Post Finance Switzerland): Generate ISO standard Delivery Instruction and Output Management using Java.
- CPM (Client: Target Canada): Improving performance by changing Inline SQL query to Stored Procedure for Change price management application
- Bancs (Client: Santander Bank UK): Developed e-banking transaction (opening fixed deposit, transferring money to different currency account). And updating the same in top tier data base
- Citi Bank (Client: Post Finance Hong Kong and Singapore): Manual Testing of user interface. Has been involved in writing test cases and test scenario.
- Technology/Tools Java, J2EE, OOPs, Spring-Batch, JSP, Servlet, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Oracle WebLogic, Eclipse IDE
- Team size: 15
 Process: Waterfall

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Aug, 2008 - May, 2012

Bachelor of Technology (B-Tech.) in Information Technology

Completed Bachelor degree from West Bengal University of Technology (Siliguri Institute of Technology) with CGPA 7.36 (out of 10)

July,2006 - June, 2008

Higher Secondary in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics

Completed Higher secondary (12th) education from Assam Higher Secondary Educational Council (Ramanuj Gupta Junior College) with 66% mark

Jan, 1996 - May, 2006

Secondary level in Science and English

Completed secondary level (10th) from Secondary Education Board of Assam (Silchar Collegiate School) with 78% mark

Curriculum Vitae Gourab Paul

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Bengali

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C1	C2	C1
C2	A2	C2	C2	A2

English Hindi

Organisational skills

- Mentorship currently responsible for training and mentoring fresher
- Team player has been awarded with best team player
- Individual contributor currently responsible for requirement gathering of the product, architectural design, development and then deploying the application to production.

Technical skills

- Languages: Nodejs, Javascript, Java, AWS cloud
- Cloud-Computing: Amazon Web Services(EC2, Lambda, server less api, Load Balancer, S3, SWF, SES, SQS, SNS), Google cloud (GCE, Firebase, Bucket), scalable Micro Services, Distributed systems
- DBMS: Oracle, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDb, DynamoDB, postgresql
- Web technology: Angular, Typescript, HTML-5, CSS-3, AJAX, Jquery, JSON, XML, JavaScript, Agile, Maven, Bootstrap-3, Junit/Mock Test, SOA, Responsive web design, Git, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Elastic search, Kibana, Web Services, MVC architecture, Spring, Design Pattern, PassportJs, Data structures and algorithms
- Tools: Eclipse, SQL developer, Intellij, MySql workbench, Visual Studio Code, jupyter notebook
- OS- Windows, Linux
- Domain knowledge: Banking, Finance and Retail domain.

Other skills

- Blogging https://oyekool.com
- Content Creation https://youtube.com/codespace

Interests

- Block chain
- Investment banking
- Deep learning

Hobbies

- Playing badminton, chess
- Trekking and exploring new places